<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.3">
  <compounddef id="indexpage" kind="page">
    <compoundname>index</compoundname>
    <title></title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Welcome to the A* Pathfinding Project Documentation page. Here you will find the documentation for the system. You can browse through every class and variable, though not everything is documented yet, I hope you will still be able to find what you are looking for.</para><para><htmlonly> &lt;div class=&quot;tinyshadow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/frontpage.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</htmlonly></para><sect1 id="index_1getstarted">
<title>Get Started With The A* Pathfinding Project</title>
<para>Check out the <ref refid="getstarted" kindref="compound">get started </ref> page for instructions on how to get started using the system.<linebreak/>
</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1upgrade">
<title>Upgrading from A* Pathfinding Project 2.9x</title>
<para>Look <ref refid="upgrading" kindref="compound">here </ref> for more info on how to upgrade from 2.9x to 3.x.<linebreak/>
</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1pro">
<title>Buy Pro</title>
<para>The A* <ref refid="namespace_pathfinding" kindref="compound">Pathfinding</ref> Project has got a Free version and a Pro version, the Pro version has got a lot of cool extra features such as multithreading, automatic navmesh generation and more. Check out the <ulink url="http://www.arongranberg.com/unity/a-pathfinding/free-vs-pro/">Free vs Pro comparison page</ulink>.<linebreak/>
 You can buy the Pro version <ulink url="http://www.arongranberg.com/shop/a-pathfinding-project-pro/">here</ulink> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1errors">
<title>Errors?</title>
<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Getting the vertices &gt; 60000 error message?<linebreak/>
 A lot of users report getting the vertices &gt; 60000 error message, this is as far as I know a Unity bug, I can unfortunately not do anything to fix it.<linebreak/>
 It might help to turn off Show Unwalkable Nodes, or to turn off Show Graphs altogether.<linebreak/>
 [Update] According to what I have heard, this is now fixed in Unity 3.5.3J</para></listitem><listitem><para>Getting errors in MonoDevelop where the functions contains default parameter values?<linebreak/>
 Select: Tools &gt; Preferences &gt; Unity &gt; Debugger and turn off &quot;Build project in MonoDevelop&quot;.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Getting errors where some classes in the A* <ref refid="namespace_pathfinding" kindref="compound">Pathfinding</ref> Project do not seem to have some members they ought to have. Check for if any of the classes in your project have a name identical to one in the A* <ref refid="namespace_pathfinding" kindref="compound">Pathfinding</ref> Project and if so, change the name of them or put them in a namespace. It will cause trouble if they are in the global namespace. I try to put my classes in namespaces, but unfortunately it will still cause troubles if ANY of the conflicting classes is in the global namespace. </para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
